Szymon Socha

linkedIn/szymon-socha | github/szymonsocha | szymonsocha.github.io

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with experience in gaming industry and economic background. Data Science and Business Analytics final year student at the University of Warsaw. Uses statistical modelling and machine learning algorithms to find new patterns and relationships in data to drive business value. Passionate about using data to solve real-world problems. Avid traveler.

EDUCATION

MSc. Data Science and Business Analytics

Warsaw, PL | 2021 - present

UNIVERSITY OF WARSAW

Awards: Dean's List 2022 (Top 7%)

Coursework: Machine Learning I, Machine Learning II, Unsupervised Learning, Advanced Econometrics, Applied Finance, Statistics, Python, Advanced Programming in R. Big Data Analytics, Algorithms for Data Science

BSc. Computer Science and Econometrics

Warsaw, PL | 2018 - 2021

UNIVERSITY OF WARSAW

GPA: 4.5/5

Thesis: "The influence of COVID-19 pandemic on the music streaming consumption." An econometric OLS model constructed and tested with R programming language. Python programming language used for data manipulation

Coursework: Machine Learning, Econometrics, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Time Series, Probability Calculus, Finance, Python, R, SQL, C++

WORK EXPERIENCE

FLYING WILD HOG | DATA SCIENTIST (JUNIOR)

Warsaw (Remote), PL | Jan 2022 - present

- Analyse telemetry data of video games (R, SQL) and implement dashboards and reports in RMarkdown and Shiny
- Develop ETL processes with BigQuery and MongoDB
- Collaborate with UX Research team members in combining quantitative and qualitative research findings
- Work closely with different game development teams and editorial teams around the world in order to understand their requirements and questions related to a project

PUBLICIS GROUPE | DATA SCIENCE ASSISTANT

Warsaw, PL | Sep 2021 - Nov 2021

- Econometric modelling project
- Data cleaning and processing with the use of Python and R and building custom R tools for econometric analysis

TESTRONIC | QA TESTER

Warsaw, PL | Feb 2018 - Oct 2018 and Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

• Detect and report bugs (in English), software flaws and design issues on a daily basis (JIRA).

PROJECTS

NEURAL NETWORK PERFORMANCE COMPARISON PYTHON, NEURAL NETWORK, LIGHTGBM, XGBOOST, RANDOM FOREST Comparison of neural network performance with other ML algorithms for two different types of data (image classification and regression).

TRAFFIC PREDICTION ☑

PYTHON, SKLEARN, RANDOM FOREST, LINEAR REGRESSION, KNN, SVM, RMD

Traffic prediction using multiple ML algorithms. Data manipulation and feature engineering.

DRUG USE CLASSIFICATION 2

PYTHON, KNN, LOGISTIC REGRESSION, SVC, RMD

Drug use prediction using multiple ML algorithms. Data manipulation and feature engineering. Balancing data with SMOTE+Tomek. Cross Validation used for parameter tuning.

SKILLS

Tech stack: R (tidyverse, dplyr, ggplot2, Rmd, Shiny), Python (sklearn, pandas, numpy), SQL (BigQuery, KQL), Git, Jenkins **Expertise:** Machine Learning and Econometric data modelling, clusterization, dimension reduction, statistics, hypothesis testing **Soft skills:** Problem-solving, Stress management, Decision-making, Time management, Communication, Attention to detail